2. EQ. Having to worry about our IQ is bad enough, and now there's something called
an EQ. Do we have to stress about that too? The answer is yes and no. Your EQ stands for
Emotional Quotient. It's a measure of how well you understand your own feelings and
those of other people. People with high EQs are very aware of their emotions and those
of others. They manage their emotions well. Emotions may not seem to be important for
serious life issues like school and work. However, we are discovering that, in fact,
having a good understanding of emotions is extremely important in any group situation.
Others are always looking for employees with good people skills, right? Your EQ is just
that, your people skills. People with high EQs become influential leaders and helpful
managers who understand how to deal with stressed employees. They understand how to use people's
feelings to achieve their goals, whether to create trust within a team or create passion
for a project. Outside of work, a high EQ is connected to romantic success. Understanding
your partner's emotions can certainly help you create a solid relationship. There are many ways
to measure your EQ. Most ask you to perform different emotional problem-solving tasks.
Testing your EQ is a useful way to find out how well you read emotions. If you think your EQ
might be low, there are ways to improve it. First, get in touch with your emotions. Think
about how they affect your actions. When you feel your emotions leading you to a bad action,
see if you can stop it. Then, concentrate on other people. See if you can identify their
emotions and emotional reasons for their actions. In this way, you will build patience,
compassion, and a strong EQ.